see with each other things like religion
and race and gender these things serve
only to divide us and give us things to
argue about them to be confrontational
about can we instead maybe try and find
a little bit of common ground some ideas
will bring us together some ideas that
can unite us because it is really
important that we unite and come
together to try and fight the ever
increasing inequality that's going on in
this world our system office becomes an
opponent simply not explainable it is
not equitable
it is not sensible our financial system
creates nothing but debt it in slays
individual it is plays Nations it
inflate government into sub textual
inability to pay off their debt they
they have to restructure their economy
as the banks tell them to do it
political systems of creating leaders
who are ever more extreme as a more
divisive look at Trump look at the pen
that the rate of inequality is
increasing exponentially that you would
have heard in January of this year there
was an article in the papers about how
the richest eight people in this world
eight people the richest eight people
have the same wealth as the poorest 3.7
billion people 3.7 billion people here
eight people here they have the same
well how can this be right it's insane
in many ways that potentiates our
educational system does not preparer
to be challenging about life we just
listen and do as we're told we have done
down to the point where our minds have
become fertile soil that I missed with
marketers and advertisers and propaganda
clamp in their calls are for the blatant
reasons of acquisition of resources we
don't erect because we want the oil we
go to Afghanistan because you want their
lithium and because we want to late
pipeline their every single war we
fought for the last 50 years has been
for one reason and one reason only
gaining control of the local resources
and installing permanent military
presence there plenty of money right oh
honey route to buy walls with plenty of
money over bailout bankers win please
give money to refurbish our private
artists losing money was stupid high tea
to rail damages and yet no money for
toilet paper or Princeton's in our
school no money to keep accident any
moment on water open consumerism and
credit of completely out of control
workers are exploited all over the world
being paid less than a dollar a day that
the quote will out the ground no
protective equipment children as young
as four going there Peter have bundle
for all mobile pose we cannot go on live
it but bloody met of this dysfunctional
in many vain anyway
not to mention unbelievably waste our
energy is still now being produced
primarily by burning fossil fuel
despite the fact batteries have been
around since 1800 the old cells have
been around in 1839 solar panel since
1954 win
eles and water mills have been around
for centuries they've been generating
power for a hundred years now we've got
geothermal we've got tidal power these
things have not even begun to be
exploited yet why not because oil
companies like to tell us all and they
control our government to the point
where they are now allowed to drill in
the Arctic they are allowed to drill in
Greenland they're allowed the
permanently defile the face of the earth
so that we can continue to buy more oil
of the 32 million cars currently
registered in the UK at any given moment
between eighty and ninety nine percent
of those cars or Tiffany parked on the
side of the road not doing anything not
working for us all of that metal all of
that rubber all of that car just sitting
there not serving it knocking two lanes
Oh with harmony Park Park where traffic
cannot pass through in a sensible world
we would have come up with some kind of
car sharing scheme by now where a dozen
people jointly owned one part and they
figure out how to share it sensibly
between them why are we not on this very
simple changing tired refueling card
insuring cards and on seeing cars
replacing upgrading financing new cars
all of these things of significant
revenue streams of big oil and car
companies put in their interest so
having to buy as many cars as possible
despite the fact it's unbelievably
wasteful why do we still get all of our
energy go slowly
vegetable well we'll be producing it
mostly using sustainable renewable
sources not polluting actually not
creating piles of nuclear waste which is
still going to be radioactive 100,000
years time oh god micro unit interior
needs a little bit of a prompt and our
farm is another ridiculously way to
think our poornima page cut by our
husband to ovaries drop painting it
another payment destroy and paint prop
the introduction of dude in the western
well it's more than enough to feed all
the poor people in the starving parts of
the world our pharmaceutical company
makes hundreds of billions of pounds of
profits every single year and yet we
still have upwards of a hundred thousand
people die every single day on this
planet a third of the children because
of poverty and because of pretend ology
in essence the well surely these people
not happen the whole space
they don't unnie they talk Ulrika told
their family instead the dull boring
dangerous job I celebrated I spend with
their families or measure our work our
education unsafe if the year our
education degrees inside to train people
to work in factories see them very dog
the pets the jobs that are now being
automated in the modern world an
education system should be created
needed to be innovative to collaborate
cooperate come up with creative
solutions problem rather than teaching
them apart from sole pointless fact
which they can look up on the internet
and then examining them on their ability
to regurgitate those back and if you do
a good drop they get rewarded with an A
if this is not a sensible way to run an
educational business then we do not live
in a sensible world do we in our world
you're no more concerned without drums
than they are with learning them
I will concern with popularity and they
are with integrity a more concerned with
image than they are with character
walking serving blame than they are with
responsibility now well people spend
more time with their phones than they do
to their friends in our world
people spend more money on servicing
their debt than they do on servicing
their families in our world 70% 70% of
arable land is given over growing deep
the cattle rather than growing through
the piece
we overproduce trade we that I've done
with send paste subsea zoom company to
drop down the rainforests to make Gupta
cattle those cattle are then fed on
grain which has been transported sales
miles over to we over used to be too
much meat
what do we do with it we grind up the
beef I've seen it back to the next
generation of tau that is where the BSE
crisis came from this is insanity
this is madness so what are we supposed
to loot what are we the people supposed
to loot when our systems no longer
server and the whole financial Eclipse
autism has been rigged to serve only
they very very beautiful 50 top what are
we supposed to how can we change the
world
yes well it's not an easy one but it has
to begin at last root level it has to be
given up but or 300 million people atop
we're currently running things they have
no interest in changing anything
everything's great far as they're
concerned the four or five billion
people have had the hospitable that up
well they're just living hand-to-mouth
they'd be doing anything they can they
today to provide so it's up to us it's
the middle class in the big countries we
are the right we're going to have the
same thing how do we do that by well you
can won't buy all of this bullshit here
argue about whose God is better
whether you're red or blue when you're a
livable my daughter or an Everton
supporter this is madness we need to
find common ground we need to find ways
in which we can unite things that we
agree on people won't buy the stuff with
its River
we're always industry about job let's
leave that I think that the things that
we can actually cooperate
is an amazing thing using the power of
the internet we can communicate ideas
with each other
one community comes out of the way to
solve a problem they can instantly
communicate that solution to the rest of
the world other communities can take
that solution modify adapt it improve it
to save it back out there again repeat
all over the world collaborating with
each other sharing ideas sharing food we
become our own three to four Oh problem
turn away from the centralized resource
control subjects of government and
finance and eventually in basically be
not even included they become how
they've been exactly they will become
irrelevant finally then they made
collapse has been built that wall
resembling a human society amount of the
problems others they're pretty
multiplier fake without very much worth
anyone will think a little bit ago he
sit here it'll still pay to entice if
you want to learn more mostly it's about
thinking about the things because really
we are talking about an exhibition
leveling out yet this is the reason
their human being or the dominant
species on this planet right now it'll
become of our ability to collaborate and
work together and share all of this
what's your angle de argumentum severe
the division the separatist this is the
beginning to the end of us as a species
if we can't recruit I'll figure out a
way the rebar difference and decide come
together we we are coming to an end at
the dominance think God is mine
thanks very much